<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd" [ <!ENTITY rsquo "’"> <!ENTITY ndash "–"> ] ><html  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ac="http://www.atlassian.com/schema/confluence/4/ac/" xmlns:ri="http://www.atlassian.com/schema/confluence/4/ri/" xml:lang="en" lang="en"><head><title>Windows Security Identifier (Dictionary Entry)</title></head><body><ac:structured-macro ac:name="details" ac:schema-version="1" data-layout="default" ac:macro-id="2c14103c-f8a6-4d15-bcc9-f7312bbc0e2d"><ac:rich-text-body><table data-layout="default"><colgroup><col style="width: 168.0px;" /><col style="width: 558.0px;" /></colgroup><tbody><tr><th><p style="text-align: right;"><strong>Contexts</strong></p></th><td><p>IAM, IT, Windows</p></td></tr><tr><th><p style="text-align: right;"><strong>Term</strong></p></th><td><h1>Windows Security Identifier</h1></td></tr><tr><th><p style="text-align: right;"><strong>Alternate Forms</strong></p></th><td><ul><li><p>Security Identifier</p></li><li><p>SID</p></li></ul></td></tr><tr><th><p style="text-align: right;"><strong>Definitions</strong></p></th><td><blockquote><p><strong>Security identifiers</strong> </p><p>Instead of using names (which might or might not be unique) to identify entities that perform actions in a system, Windows uses security identifiers (SIDs). Users have SIDs, as do local and domain groups, local computers, domains, domain members, and services. A SID is a variable-length numeric value that consists of a SID structure revision number, a 48-bit identifier authority value, and a variable number of 32-bit subauthority or relative identifier (RID) values. The authority value identifies the agent that issued the SID, and this agent is typically a Windows local system or a domain. Subauthority values identify trustees relative to the issuing authority, and RIDs are simply a way for Windows to create unique SIDs based on a common base SID. Because SIDs are long and Windows takes care to generate truly random values within each SID, it is virtually impossible for Windows to issue the same SID twice on machines or domains anywhere in the world.</p><p>When displayed textually, each SID carries an S prefix, and its various components are separated with hyphens like so:</p><p>S-1-5-21-1463437245-1224812800-863842198-1128</p><p>In this SID, the revision number is 1, the identifier authority value is 5 (the Windows security authority), and four subauthority values plus one RID (1128) make up the remainder of the SID. This SID is a domain SID, but a local computer on the domain would have a SID with the same revision number, identifier authority value, and number of subauthority values.</p></blockquote><p style="text-align: right;"> (<ac:link ac:card-appearance="inline"><ri:page ri:space-key="BIB" ri:content-title="Russinovich et al., 2017" ri:version-at-save="1" /><ac:link-body>Russinovich et al., 2017</ac:link-body></ac:link>, p. 625).</p></td></tr><tr><th><p style="text-align: right;"><strong>Related Terms</strong></p></th><td><p /></td></tr><tr><th><p style="text-align: right;"><strong>See Also</strong></p></th><td><p /></td></tr></tbody></table></ac:rich-text-body></ac:structured-macro><p /></body></html>